Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or dramacool.li
دعم الإدارة شاهد على kissasia.cam أو dramacool.li
Every yak in Xizang has a name.
لكل ثور ياك في شيزانغ اسم.
Can you believe it?
هل تصدق ذلك؟
Loudima.
لوديما.
Donggeimai.
دونججيماي.
Dunzhu Zhuoma.
دونزو زوما.
No, no, no. I'm not talking about them.
لا، لا، لا. أنا لا أتحدث عنهم.
But this little one.
لكن هذا الصغير.
I need to put an ear tag
أحتاج إلى وضع علامة على الأذن
on its ear.
على مقلوبها.
We've been in a standoff
لقد كنا في حالة جمود
for five minutes and thirteen seconds.
لمدة خمس دقائق وثلاث عشرة ثانية.
The last time I
آخر مرة كنت فيها
looked at a cow this intently
نظرت إلى بقرة بهذا التركيز
was this one.
كان هذا هو.
And this one.
وهذا أيضاً.
And... wait, wrong.
و... انتظر، هذا خطأ.
This is the one.
هذا هو المطلوب.
Daddy, Daddy, I miss you!
أبي، أبي، اشتقت إليك!
Niu Niu and Niu Niu.
نيو نيو ونيو نيو.
have been a constant in my life.
لقد كانوا ثابتين في حياتي.
What does this weird uncle want?
ماذا يريد هذا العم الغريب؟
Little Niu Niu.
ليتل نيو نيو.
I'm going to give you an ear tag.
سأضع لك علامة على أذنك.
It won't hurt at all.
لن يكون مؤلماً على الإطلاق.
I don't believe you.
أنا لا أصدقك.
Don't come any closer!
لا تقترب أكثر!
Be good, be good, be good.
كن طيباً، كن طيباً، كن طيباً.
Don't come over.
لا تأتي.
If you come any closer, I'll...
إذا اقتربت أكثر من ذلك، فسأفعل...
Alright, come on.
حسناً، هيا بنا.
I... I... I'll fight him!
أنا... أنا... سأقاتله!
Why did I come here?
لماذا أتيت إلى هنا؟
Leaving my job
ترك وظيفتي
and Shenzhen, where I lived for over a decade,
وشنتشن، حيث عشت لأكثر من عقد من الزمان،
to come to Xizang, over three thousand kilometers away,
أن يأتي إلى شيزانغ، التي تبعد أكثر من ثلاثة آلاف كيلومتر،
to wrestle with a yak?
مصارعة الياك؟
My name is Zhang Zhaoyuan, from Shenzhen.
اسمي تشانغ تشاويوان، من شنتشن.
I came to Xizang to promote yak insurance.
جئت إلى شيزانغ للترويج لتأمين الياك.
Zhaoyuan.
تشاويوان.
The company wants to strengthen
ترغب الشركة في تعزيز
its insurance operations in Xizang,
عملياتها التأمينية في شيزانغ،
Qinghai, and other regions.
تشينغهاي، ومناطق أخرى.
To promote the national agricultural support policies,
لتعزيز سياسات الدعم الزراعي الوطنية،
we need to send our best people
نحن بحاجة إلى إرسال أفضل رجالنا
to insure the yaks.
لتأمين حيوانات الياك.
The work will be very challenging.
سيكون العمل صعباً للغاية.
Are you willing to go?
هل أنت مستعد للذهاب؟
Sending you
أرسل إليك
is because we believe you have the ability
ذلك لأننا نؤمن بقدراتك
to fight the tough battles
لخوض المعارك الصعبة
and create miracles.
ويصنع المعجزات.
Hello.
مرحبًا.
This is
هذا هو
Brother Zhang.
الأخ تشانغ.
This... this is our savior.
هذا... هذا هو منقذنا.
The big boss from the Shenzhen headquarters.
المدير الكبير من المقر الرئيسي في شنتشن.
Hello, boss.
مرحباً سيدي الرئيس.
I'm not some big boss.
أنا لست رئيسًا كبيرًا.
We're all just working folks.
كلنا مجرد أناس عاملون.
Hello.
مرحبًا.
My name is Zhang Zhaoyuan.
اسمي تشانغ تشاويوان.
From now on, we're colleagues.
من الآن فصاعدًا، نحن زملاء.
What should I call you?
ماذا أناديكَ؟
Brother Zhang.
الأخ تشانغ.
You can just call me Hazha.
يمكنك أن تناديني هازا.
I'm really just here to support.
أنا هنا فقط لأقدم الدعم.
I'll be counting on you from now on.
سأعتمد عليك من الآن فصاعدًا.
Of course, of course.
بالتأكيد، بالتأكيد.
Brother Zhang.
الأخ تشانغ.
It was too late yesterday,
لقد فات الأوان بالأمس،
we didn't have time to chat properly.
لم يكن لدينا وقت كافٍ للدردشة بشكل مناسب.
You know, we've
كما تعلمون، لقد
been working for a few months now.
أعمل في هذا المجال منذ بضعة أشهر.
To be honest,
صراحة،
it's been full of difficulties.
لقد كانت مليئة بالصعوبات.
I feel like my job
أشعر أن وظيفتي
is about to be lost.
على وشك أن يضيع.
You know,
أنت تعرف،
if I really had to leave Xizang,
لو اضطررت حقاً لمغادرة شيزانغ،
I'd actually be a bit reluctant.
في الحقيقة، سأكون متردداً بعض الشيء.
What specific difficulties are there?
ما هي الصعوبات المحددة الموجودة؟
Tell me.
أخبرني.
Well, Brother,
حسناً يا أخي،
let me report to you first.
دعني أقدم لك تقريراً أولاً.
It's like this.
الأمر هكذا.
Look,
ينظر،
our equipment
معداتنا
has been ready for a while.
كان جاهزاً منذ فترة.
See, it can display
انظر، يمكنه العرض
the yak count, location,
عدد حيوانات الياك، الموقع،
and vital signs.
والعلامات الحيوية.
It can show everything.
بإمكانه أن يُظهر كل شيء.
It's just that the locals
الأمر ببساطة أن السكان المحليين
still can't quite accept it.
ما زلت لا أستطيع تقبله تماماً.
We've done
لقد فعلنا
several rounds of work.
عدة جولات من العمل.
The results still aren't good.
النتائج لا تزال غير جيدة.
Right.
يمين.
But that's not specific enough.
لكن هذا ليس محدداً بما فيه الكفاية.
For example, last month,
على سبيل المثال، الشهر الماضي،
Wangmu's yak
ياك وانغمو
got eaten by a snow leopard.
التهمه نمر ثلجي.
I thought to myself,
فكرت في نفسي،
"Even a blind sparrow won't starve."
"حتى العصفور الأعمى لن يموت جوعاً."
Isn't this a great opportunity
أليست هذه فرصة رائعة؟
to promote yak insurance?
للترويج لتأمين الياك؟
So the two of us went.
وهكذا ذهبنا نحن الاثنان.
Guess what Wangmu said?
خمن ماذا قالت وانغم؟
"If it's eaten, then it's eaten.
"إذا تم أكله، فقد تم أكله."
This way the snow leopard won't starve."
وبهذه الطريقة لن يموت النمر الثلجي جوعاً.
I was completely stunned at the time.
لقد صُدمت تماماً في ذلك الوقت.
This herder
هذا الراعي
felt it was just fate.
شعرتُ أنه مجرد قدر.
But the yak can't
لكن الياك لا يستطيع
just be eaten by a snow leopard, right?
أليس من المفترض أن يلتهمها نمر ثلجي؟
That's exactly what I'm saying.
هذا بالضبط ما أقوله.
I understand the basic situation.
أفهم الوضع الأساسي.
But it's okay.
لكن لا بأس.
The more difficult it is,
كلما زادت صعوبة الأمر،
the more challenging it is.
كلما زادت صعوبته.
Let me introduce myself.
دعوني أقدم نفسي.
I'm from the Shenzhen headquarters.
أنا من المقر الرئيسي في شنتشن.
A six-time consecutive Quarterly Star.
حائز على جائزة النجم الفصلي ست مرات متتالية.
No matter how tough the project,
مهما كانت صعوبة المشروع،
I can handle it.
أستطيع التعامل مع الأمر.
One month's time.
بعد شهر واحد.
Within the jurisdiction,
ضمن نطاق الاختصاص القضائي،
one hundred thousand yaks
مئة ألف من حيوانات الياك
must all be insured.
يجب أن تكون جميعها مؤمنة.
Take it easy, take it easy.
خذ الأمور ببساطة، خذ الأمور ببساطة.
Go away. Don't be impatient.
اذهب بعيدًا. لا تكن متسرعًا.
They are family.
إنهم عائلة.
They've lived here for decades.
لقد عاشوا هنا لعقود.
You city folk,
يا أهل المدينة،
why are you disturbing them?
لماذا تزعجهم؟
What is he saying?
ماذا يقول؟
Why is he chasing us out?
لماذا يطردنا؟
He's not chasing us out.
هو لا يطردنا.
He's not chasing us.
إنه لا يطاردنا.
We are here to
نحن هنا من أجل
protect your money.
احمِ أموالك.
Just with a piece of paper?
مجرد ورقة؟
Can you make his dog stop barking?
هل يمكنك إيقاف نباح كلبه؟
What is he saying?
ماذا يقول؟
Is he cursing my dog?
هل يلعن كلبي؟
Your dog keeps barking.
كلبك ينبح باستمرار.
It's giving me a headache.
إنه يسبب لي صداعاً.
Stop barking!
توقف عن النباح!
Don't you shout!
لا تصرخ!
You need to be
يجب أن تكون
more polite to our client.
أكثر تهذيباً مع عميلنا.
He just can't understand
إنه ببساطة لا يستطيع أن يفهم
what this thing is.
ما هذا الشيء؟
The state is spending so much money for you.
الدولة تنفق الكثير من المال من أجلك.
You'll have security afterwards.
ستتمتع بالأمان بعد ذلك.
If it's lost or dies,
إذا فُقد أو مات،
you'll get compensation.
ستحصل على تعويض.
What a great thing!
يا له من شيء رائع!
We're not lying to you.
نحن لا نكذب عليك.
Brother Zhang is a good man!
الأخ تشانغ رجل صالح!
You... you just don't get it, do you?
أنت... أنت ببساطة لا تفهم الأمر، أليس كذلك؟
Are you speaking Chinese to me?
هل تتحدث معي باللغة الصينية؟
Brother Zhang.
الأخ تشانغ.
Here, have a sip.
تفضل، خذ رشفة.
No need, I'm long over the altitude sickness.
لا داعي لذلك، لقد تجاوزت دوار المرتفعات منذ زمن طويل.
Which family are we visiting today?
أي عائلة نزورها اليوم؟
We're going to Grandma Zhuoma's house today.
سنذهب اليوم إلى منزل الجدة زوما.
Let me tell you,
دعني أخبرك،
she has a lot of yaks.
لديها الكثير من حيوانات الياك.
That's good.
هذا جيد.
It's just that she's a bit stubborn.
الأمر فقط أنها عنيدة بعض الشيء.
What's there to fear about stubbornness?
ما الذي يدعو للخوف من العناد؟
Our policies are so good.
سياساتنا ممتازة للغاية.
How could we not promote them successfully?
كيف لنا ألا نروج لهم بنجاح؟
Let's go back to the beginning.
لنعد إلى البداية.
Brother Zhang! Brother Zhang!
أخي تشانغ! أخي تشانغ!
Quick, quick, quick! Got it!
بسرعة، بسرعة، بسرعة! فهمت!
Brother Zhang, come quick! Brother Zhang!
أخي تشانغ، تعال بسرعة! أخي تشانغ!
Quick, grab it!
أسرع، احصل عليه!
Quick, quick! Don't move, don't move!
بسرعة، بسرعة! لا تتحرك، لا تتحرك!
Grandma Zhuoma!
الجدة زوما!
No, no, no, don't!
لا، لا، لا، لا تفعل!
You agreed to put on the ear tag!
لقد وافقت على وضع علامة الأذن!
You said it was okay!
قلتَ إنه لا بأس!
Who told you to poke a hole in its ear?
من سمح لك بثقب أذنه؟
Grandma Zhuoma
الجدة زوما
This ear tag is meant to go on the ear.
هذه العلامة مخصصة لوضعها على الأذن.
It can't go anywhere else.
لا يمكن أن يذهب إلى أي مكان آخر.
You have to understand.
عليك أن تفهم.
Then don't put it on.
إذن لا ترتديه.
No.
لا.
Look at all these yaks behind you.
انظر إلى كل هذه حيوانات الياك خلفك.
They all have it.
جميعهم يمتلكونه.
See, they're happily grazing, full of life.
انظر، إنهم يرعون بسعادة، مفعمين بالحياة.
So much energy.
طاقة هائلة.
They can handle it.
بإمكانهم التعامل مع الأمر.
It can't.
لا يمكن ذلك.
It's still young.
لا يزال صغيراً.
It's afraid of pain.
إنه يخاف من الألم.
It just called for me to save it.
كان الأمر يستدعي مني حفظه.
Called for you to save it.
طلب منك حفظه.
Yes.
نعم.
No, Grandma, about this...
لا يا جدتي، بخصوص هذا...
Look, we get our ears pierced too.
انظروا، نحن أيضاً نقوم بثقب آذاننا.
It doesn't hurt. Just a quick pinch.
لا يؤلم. مجرد قرصة سريعة.
It's over in a tiny moment.
ينتهي الأمر في لحظة خاطفة.
I'm afraid of pain.
أنا أخاف من الألم.
I don't get my ears pierced.
أنا لا أثقب أذني.
I don't wear earrings either.
أنا أيضاً لا أرتدي الأقراط.
I won't allow it.
لن أسمح بذلك.
Alright then.
حسناً إذاً.
Brother Zhang.
الأخ تشانغ.
So here's the thing.
إذن إليكم الأمر.
Just now, this little yak...
قبل قليل، هذا الياك الصغير...
It cried for help.
لقد صرخ طلباً للمساعدة.
Grandma heard it.
سمعت جدتي ذلك.
So she came over to save it.
لذا أتت لإنقاذه.
Come on, don't be ridiculous.
هيا، لا تكن سخيفاً.
It called out twice.
أصدر صوتاً مرتين.
She could hear it from that far?
هل استطاعت سماعه من تلك المسافة؟
And she could understand what it said?
وهل استطاعت أن تفهم ما قيل؟
It's like this for us.
الأمر كذلك بالنسبة لنا.
People...
الناس...
and cattle...
والماشية...
or other animals...
أو حيوانات أخرى...
There's this kind of...
هناك نوع من...
It's just a sudden... connection.
إنها مجرد علاقة مفاجئة...
I get it.
أحصل عليه.
Telepathy, right?
التخاطر، أليس كذلك؟
Yes, telepathy.
نعم، التخاطر.
Bro.
أخ.
How about this?
ما رأيك بهذا؟
Let's just skip this little yak.
دعونا نتجاهل هذا الموضوع التافه.
How can we do that?
كيف يمكننا فعل ذلك؟
We can't make exceptions.
لا يمكننا تقديم استثناءات.
What's this yak's name?
ما اسم هذا الياك؟
What's it called?
ما اسمه؟
Niu Niu.
نيو نيو.
It's Niu Niu.
إنها نيو نيو.
I...
أنا...
I asked for its name.
سألت عن اسمه.
I know it's a yak.
أعلم أنه ثور الياك.
Its name is Niu Niu.
اسمها نيو نيو.
It's just called Niu Niu.
اسمها ببساطة نيو نيو.
Yes, Niu Niu.
نعم نيو نيو.
You name your yaks...
سمِّ حيوانات الياك خاصتك...
so casually?
بكل هذه العفوية؟
No, not casually.
لا، ليس بشكل عرضي.
Its name in Xizang language...
اسمها في لغة شيزانغ...
is Yak.
هو الياك.
Translated into Chinese...
مترجم إلى الصينية...
it's Niu Niu.
إنها نيو نيو.
Niu Niu.
نيو نيو.
Niu Niu, right?
نيو نيو، صحيح؟
Yes.
نعم.
Grandma Zhuoma.
الجدة زوما.
Its name is Niu Niu.
اسمها نيو نيو.
What a coincidence!
يا لها من مصادفة!
My daughter's nickname is Niu Niu too.
لقب ابنتي هو نيو نيو أيضاً.
See, how amazing is that?
أرأيت، كم هذا مذهل؟
So when I see it...
لذلك عندما أراه...
it's like seeing my own daughter.
الأمر أشبه برؤية ابنتي.
Think about it.
فكر في الأمر.
If I were putting this ear tag on my daughter...
لو كنت سأضع هذه العلامة على أذن ابنتي...
how could I use force?
كيف يمكنني استخدام القوة؟
In a moment, I'll just...
بعد لحظة، سأفعل...
gently...
بلطف...
press it like this.
اضغط عليه هكذا.
It won't hurt at all.
لن يكون مؤلماً على الإطلاق.
No pain.
لا ألم.
Brother Zhang! Brother Zhang! Brother Zhang!
أخي تشانغ! أخي تشانغ! أخي تشانغ!
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
هيا بنا، هيا بنا، هيا بنا!
No.
لا.
What on earth did you translate to her?
ما الذي ترجمته لها بحق السماء؟
I just translated exactly what you said.
لقد ترجمت ما قلته بالضبط.
What? What did you say?
ماذا؟ ماذا قلت؟
This Grandma Zhuoma...
هذه الجدة زوما...
has quite the temper.
لديه مزاج حاد للغاية.
What exactly did you tell her?
ماذا قلت لها بالضبط؟
Did you tell her before...
هل أخبرتها من قبل؟
that buying yak insurance...
شراء تأمين الياك...
protects the herders' interests?
هل يحمي مصالح الرعاة؟
Brother Zhang, I really did say it.
أخي تشانغ، لقد قلت ذلك فعلاً.
And I said everything I was supposed to.
وقلت كل ما كان عليّ قوله.
We have to keep saying it, over and over.
علينا أن نكرر ذلك مراراً وتكراراً.
We're in insurance.
نحن نعمل في مجال التأمين.
There's no secret trick, right?
لا توجد خدعة سرية، أليس كذلك؟
It's just about repeatedly...
الأمر يتكرر بشكل متكرر...
putting our message out there.
ننشر رسالتنا.
Doing promotion is like ironing clothes.
الترويج يشبه كيّ الملابس.
You push your idea out...
أنت تدفع بفكرتك إلى الخارج...
and then smooth it back in.
ثم قم بتسويته مرة أخرى.
That's how you leave your mark.
هكذا تترك بصمتك.
Yes, bro.
نعم يا أخي.
But we don't iron clothes.
لكننا لا نكوي الملابس.
It's an analogy.
إنه تشبيه.
You understand analogies, right?
أنت تفهم التشبيهات، أليس كذلك؟
When we first got here...
عندما وصلنا إلى هنا لأول مرة...
how little yak insurance had we sold?
كم كانت نسبة مبيعاتنا من تأمين الياك ضئيلة؟
And how many head do we have now?
وكم عدد الرؤوس التي لدينا الآن؟
That's your ironed clothes.
هذه ملابسك المكوية.
Right.
يمين.
That makes sense.
هذا منطقي.
We've made progress.
لقد أحرزنا تقدماً.
Brother Zhang, you're amazing.
أخي تشانغ، أنت رائع.
I give you a thumbs up.
أعطيك علامة إعجاب.
Quarterly Star.
النجمة الفصلية.
Six times.
ست مرات.
Brother Zhang, Brother Zhang.
أخي تشانغ، أخي تشانغ.
Are you okay?
هل أنت بخير؟
I'm fine.
أنا بخير.
There's dung.
يوجد روث.
These darn yaks
هذه الياك اللعينة
Why do they poop so much?
لماذا يتبرزون كثيراً؟
And every pile is so huge.
وكل كومة ضخمة للغاية.
What's wrong with big?
ما المشكلة في الحجم الكبير؟
You just don't understand.
أنت ببساطة لا تفهم.
Yak dung is incredibly useful.
روث الياك مفيد للغاية.
It can fuel fires, boil milk tea.
يمكن استخدامه لإشعال النيران، وغلي شاي الحليب.
Build houses, raise courtyard walls.
قم ببناء المنازل، وارفع جدران الأفنية.
Be carved into decorations.
يمكن نحتها لتصبح زخارف.
Even the meals
حتى الوجبات
we Tibetans eat at home
نحن التبتيون نأكل في المنزل
are cooked with yak dung.
يتم طهيها باستخدام روث الياك.
It tastes wonderful.
طعمه رائع.
Bro, what's wrong?
يا أخي، ما الخطب؟
Hazha!
Hazha!
You're like a blacksmith burning his own butt.
أنت مثل حداد يحرق مؤخرته.
You can't read the room.
لا يمكنك قراءة ما يدور في الغرفة.
Is this the right time
هل هذا هو الوقت المناسب؟
to talk about food with Brother Zhang?
هل نتحدث عن الطعام مع الأخ تشانغ؟
And is it right for you to mention butts?
وهل من الصواب أن تذكر المؤخرات؟
That's still better than talking about food!
هذا أفضل من الحديث عن الطعام!
Brother Zhang just ate that stuff...
لقد أكل الأخ تشانغ ذلك الشيء للتو...
Ugh!
أوف!
Are you two doing this on purpose?
هل تفعلان هذا عن قصد؟
Will you ever stop?
هل ستتوقف يوماً ما؟
Bro, it wasn't on purpose.
يا أخي، لم يكن ذلك عن قصد.
Bro.
أخ.
I'm not lying to you.
أنا لا أكذب عليك.
Once yak dung is dried,
بمجرد أن يجف روث الياك،
it has no smell at all.
ليس له رائحة على الإطلاق.
Brother Zhang.
الأخ تشانغ.
If one day
إذا حدث ذلك يوماً ما
you can accept yak dung,
يمكنك قبول روث الياك،
it will prove
سيثبت ذلك
you truly understand us.
أنت تفهمنا حقاً.
Old Mou just called to ask
اتصل أولد مو للتو ليسأل
when the two of us are going back.
عندما نعود نحن الاثنان.
This rain won't stop
هذا المطر لن يتوقف
for a while.
لفترة من الوقت.
We'll stay here tonight.
سنبقى هنا الليلة.
Sleep here?
هل تنام هنا؟
Yeah.
نعم.
Isn't this nice?
أليس هذا جميلاً؟
We have everything we need.
لدينا كل ما نحتاجه.
Wait, wait.
انتظر، انتظر.
Wipe your hands.
امسح يديك.
It's fine.
لا بأس.
Alright, alright.
حسناً، حسناً.
Have some tea to warm up.
تناول بعض الشاي لتشعر بالدفء.
Then come quickly and tell me,
ثم تعال بسرعة وأخبرني،
is this yak Dongrulai
هل هذا الياك دونغرولاي؟
or Kabu?
أو كابو؟
They all look the same.
جميعهم يبدون متشابهين.
This one...
هذا...
This yak
هذا الياك
is not Dongrulai.
ليست دونغرولاي.
This is
هذا هو
Daren's Nuo'er.
دارين نوير.
It means "treasure."
ويعني "كنز".
So this is Nuo'er.
هذا هو نو'ر.
Yes, little treasure.
نعم، يا كنز صغير.
Then look at this one.
ثم انظر إلى هذا.
This is Dongrulai, right?
هذا هو دونغرولاي، أليس كذلك؟
Nope.
لا.
This is also Daren's.
هذا أيضاً ملك لدارين.
It's called Gang.
اسمها عصابة.
It means "above" or "on top."
ويعني "فوق" أو "في الأعلى".
As far as I can see,
على حد علمي،
they all look pretty similar.
جميعها تبدو متشابهة إلى حد كبير.
What are you laughing at?
ما الذي يضحكك؟
Hearing you say that
لقد سمعتك تقول ذلك
suddenly made me think.
جعلني ذلك أفكر فجأة.
You can't tell these yaks apart,
لا يمكنك التمييز بين هذه الياك،
just like us locals
تمامًا مثلنا نحن السكان المحليين
can't understand that
لا أستطيع فهم ذلك
policy of yours.
سياستك.
Every single word in it,
كل كلمة فيه،
separately,
بشكل منفصل،
we recognize.
نحن ندرك ذلك.
But when you put those words together,
لكن عندما تجمع تلك الكلمات معًا،
we don't understand.
نحن لا نفهم.
It's leaking over there.
إنها تتسرب من هناك.
Is that okay?
هل هذا مناسب؟
Let it leak.
دعها تتسرب.
It's fine, you're not sleeping there.
لا بأس، أنت لن تنام هناك.
We're sleeping here, what's there to fear?
نحن ننام هنا، فما الذي يدعو للخوف؟
No,
لا،
your
لك
dung is getting soaked.
الروث يتبلل.
This, this...
هذا، هذا...
The dung?
الروث؟
So it gets wet, there's plenty here.
لذا، يصبح المكان رطباً، وهناك الكثير من الماء هنا.
There's lots of dry dung.
يوجد الكثير من الروث الجاف.
You know what?
أتعلم؟
When this dung is dried and burned,
عندما يجف هذا الروث ويحرق،
it's not smelly at all.
إنها ليست كريهة الرائحة على الإطلاق.
Right.
يمين.
It even has a bit of a fragrance.
بل إنها تتمتع برائحة خفيفة.
Let me tell you,
دعني أخبرك،
the yaks here
حيوانات الياك هنا
all grow up eating green grass.
جميعهم يكبرون وهم يأكلون العشب الأخضر.
Completely natural and healthy.
طبيعي وصحي تمامًا.
Let me tell you another secret.
دعني أخبرك سراً آخر.
Some yaks have great taste.
بعض حيوانات الياك تتمتع بذوق رفيع.
They eat cordyceps.
إنهم يأكلون فطر الكورديسيبس.
You know cordyceps, right?
أنت تعرف فطر الكورديسيبس، أليس كذلك؟
Stop bragging.
توقف عن التباهي.
Eating cordyceps?
تناول فطر الكورديسيبس؟
I'm really not bragging.
أنا لا أتباهى حقاً.
This...
هذا...
This here...
هذا هنا...
Isn't this it? Here.
أليس هذا هو؟ هنا.
Bro.
أخ.
Co... cordyceps?
كو... كورديسيبس؟
This is... this is dry grass.
هذا... هذا عشب جاف.
This is dry grass.
هذا عشب جاف.
Cordyceps, my foot.
فطر الكورديسيبس، يا إلهي!
I've always been curious,
لطالما كنت فضولياً،
what kind of place
أي نوع من الأماكن
Shenzhen really is.
شنتشن بالفعل كذلك.
And also,
وأيضًا،
you must be
لا بد أنك
a really
حقاً
important big shot in Shenzhen.
شخصية مهمة وذات نفوذ في شنتشن.
What big shot am I?
ما هذا التباهي الذي أبدو عليه؟
Let me tell you
دعني أخبرك
what kind of place Shenzhen is.
ما نوع المكان الذي تُعتبر عليه شنتشن؟
Shenzhen is a place
شنتشن مكان
where even the air is running.
حيث حتى الهواء يعمل.
Even the air is running?
حتى المكيف يعمل؟
What if you don't run?
ماذا لو لم تركض؟
Then you fall behind.
ثم تتخلف عن الركب.
Fall behind...
التخلف عن الركب...
Life here is
الحياة هنا
quite different.
مختلف تماماً.
Take us, for example.
خذنا نحن كمثال.
Every day,
كل يوم،
we ride horses, herd yaks,
نركب الخيل، ونرعى حيوانات الياك،
bask in the sun, drink some butter tea.
استمتع بأشعة الشمس، واشرب بعض شاي الزبدة.
When the sun sets,
عندما تغرب الشمس،
we return to the yurt.
نعود إلى الخيمة.
Sing and dance.
غنوا وارقصوا.
Life is a bit slower,
الحياة أصبحت أبطأ قليلاً،
but our hearts are never anxious.
لكن قلوبنا لا تشعر بالقلق أبداً.
We're not afraid of falling behind at all.
لسنا خائفين من التخلف عن الركب على الإطلاق.
Brother
أخ
We've only tagged two thousand.
لقد قمنا بوضع علامات على ألفي شخص فقط.
We're way off target.
نحن بعيدون كل البعد عن الهدف.
I'm the Quarterly Star.
أنا النجم الفصلي.
We have to believe in miracles.
علينا أن نؤمن بالمعجزات.
Believe in miracles.
آمن بالمعجزات.
Hurry up and fly it! I'll chase you!
أسرع وحلّق بها! سألحق بك!
Now we'll put this photo
والآن سنضع هذه الصورة
in this slot.
في هذا المكان.
Okay.
تمام.
It's flying! So cool!
إنها تطير! رائع جداً!
Every time I see it take off,
في كل مرة أراها تقلع،
my heart swells with excitement.
قلبي يفيض بالحماس.
Look!
ينظر!
You try.
جرب بنفسك.
Me? No, no, no.
أنا؟ لا، لا، لا.
Believe in yourself. You can do it.
ثق بنفسك. أنت قادر على فعلها.
Here.
هنا.
This one on the left
هذا الذي على اليسار
controls ascent and descent.
يتحكم في الصعود والهبوط.
The right one controls direction.
يتحكم الجانب الأيمن في الاتجاه.
Watching you fly every day,
أشاهدك تحلق كل يوم،
I've picked up a little.
لقد تحسنت قليلاً.
Not bad, you.
ليس سيئاً، أنت.
It's flying away! It's gone!
إنها تطير بعيداً! لقد اختفت!
Alright, alright.
حسناً، حسناً.
Fly, fly, fly!
حلّق، حلّق، حلّق!
Little Niu Niu.
ليتل نيو نيو.
We meet again.
نلتقي مجدداً.
This strange uncle
هذا العم الغريب
is trying to trick me again.
يحاول خداعي مرة أخرى.
I'm a good person.
أنا شخص جيد.
Listen to me.
استمع لي.
If we tag your ear,
إذا قمنا بوضع علامة على أذنك،
and you get lost,
وتضيع،
we can find you.
يمكننا العثور عليك.
If someday, by chance...
إذا حدث ذلك يوماً ما، بالصدفة...
I mean, just *if*...
أعني، فقط *لو*...
If you were to pass away,
إذا توفيت،
how sad and heartbroken Grandma would be.
كم ستكون جدتي حزينة ومفجوعة.
Let's pick a day
لنختر يوماً
to just give you a little tag.
مجرد إشارة بسيطة إليك.
Zhang.
تشانغ.
Grandma.
جدتي.
Yak is a good yak.
الياك هو ياك جيد.
Has a hard life.
حياته صعبة.
Difficult birth. Its mother died.
ولادة عسيرة. ماتت أمه.
It has no mother to love it.
ليس لها أم تحبها.
I love it.
أنا أحبه.
Grandma.
جدتي.
Let me show you.
دعني أريك.
Her.
ها.
My daughter.
ابنتي.
My daughter's name is Niu Niu.
اسم ابنتي نيو نيو.
It.
هو - هي.
Is called Niu Niu.
اسمها نيو نيو.
The names are the same.
الأسماء متطابقة.
I love her.
أنا أحبها.
Protect her.
احمها.
I also love it.
أنا أيضاً أحبه.
Protect it.
احمِها.
Protect.
يحمي.
Zhang.
تشانغ.
I understand.
أفهم.
I will think carefully about this.
سأفكر في هذا الأمر ملياً.